A Finding Aid to the Frank Lloyd Gallery Records, 1960-2003, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Frank Lloyd Gallery records
1960, 1974, 1988-2003
Archives of American Art
Frank Lloyd Gallery
AAA.franllog
Archival Resource Key
0.8 Linear feet
The Frank Lloyd Gallery records measure 0.8 linear feet and date from 1960 to 2003, with the bulk of records dating from 1988 to 2003. The records include correspondence, exhibition announcements and catalogs, magazine and newspaper clippings, mailers, press releases, a file for artist Beatrice Wood, and scant photographic materials.
Biographical / Historical
Frank Lloyd Gallery was established in 1996 in Santa Monica, California. The gallery exhibited contemporary ceramics, showing established U.S. artists as well as ceramicists from England, France, Holland, Mexico and Japan. Artists shown at the gallery include Peter Shire, Otto and Vivika Heino, Roseline Delisle, John Mason, Anna Silver, Wouter Dam, and many more. The gallery closed its public exhibition program in 2015, but continues to work with private collectors, museums, and commercial galleries; and represents the estates of Craig Kauffman, Peter Voulkos, and Larry Bell.
Arrangement
Due to the small size of this collection the records are arranged as one series.
Scope and Contents
The Frank Lloyd Gallery records measure 0.8 linear feet and date from 1960 to 2003, with the bulk of records dating from 1988 to 2003. The records include exhibition announcements and catalogs, magazine and newspaper clippings, mailers, press releases, and some photographic materials. Beatrice Wood's artist file consists of photos, correspondence, homemade cards, clippings, exhibition ephemera and more. Correspondence includes holiday cards, thank you notes, and scant museum correspondence.
Conditions Governing Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C., Research Center.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was donated in 2004 by Frank Lloyd, gallery owner, as part of the Nanette L. Laitman Documentation Project for Craft and Decorative Arts in America.
Art galleries, Commercial -- California; Ceramics; Lloyd, Frank, 1951-; Nanette L. Laitman Documentation Project for Craft and Decorative Arts in America
- Administrative Records, 1960-2003; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 0.8 Linear feet Box 1-2
  Scope and Contents
  Found here are exhibition announcements and catalogs, magazine and newspaper clippings, mailers, press releases, and some photographic materials. Beatrice Wood's artist file consists of photos, correspondence, homemade cards, clippings, exhibition ephemera and more. Correspondence includes holiday cards, thank you notes, and scant museum correspondence.
  - Artist File, Wood, Beatrice, 1960, 1974, 1990s; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Collection Tour Guest List and Itinerary, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Exhibition Material, Museums and Exhibitions, 1994-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Gallery Mailers and Press Releases, 1995-2001; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - List of Works Placed in Museum Collections, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Photographic Materials, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Printed Material, Art Articles and Reviews, 1988-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Printed Material, Art Articles and Reviews, 1997-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Printed Material, Exhibition Announcements, 1996-2003; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
  - Printed Material, Exhibition Catalogs, 1999-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Printed Material, Gallery Listings, 1996-2002; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5-6)